<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patrik Trefil</title>
    <link>https://patriktrefil.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Patrik Trefil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 09:50:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://patriktrefil.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programs I Use</title>
      <link>https://patriktrefil.com/programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 09:56:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patriktrefil.com/programs/</guid>
      <description>You can find my configs on GitHub.
My builds are on Gitlab.
General  Window Manager: dwm Status bar: dwmblocks Browser: Firefox Editor: nvim, vscodium Terminal: Alacritty Cloud: Mega File Manager: ranger, pcmanfm Theme: Dracula  Documents  PDF-Viewer: Zathura Markdown Latex Libre Office Books: callibre  Video  MPV VLC  Audio  MPD with ncmpcpp  Other  Password Manager: Bitwarden Notes: Joplin RSS Client: newsboat Shortcuts Daemon: sxhkd Locker: xsecurelock Redshift, safeeyes - easy on the eyes  Services  ProtonVPN Tutanota E-mail Signal IM Matrix  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://patriktrefil.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 11:27:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patriktrefil.com/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Patrik Trefil and I study Computer Science at Charles University in Prague, Czech Republic.
Here is my PGP Key
Matrix: @patrik.trefil@tchncs.de</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad (2018) Review: The best budget tablet</title>
      <link>https://patriktrefil.com/posts/ipad_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 09:50:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patriktrefil.com/posts/ipad_review/</guid>
      <description>iPad 2018 is currently the cheapest tablet sold by Apple. This model is an excellent option for students because of Apple Pencil support. It performs well in easy tasks such as browsing the web, checking e-mails and watching Netflix. Let&#39;s dive deeper into the pros and cons of this product.
It is an Apple product, so everything works well with their other products. Using hand-off to continue the work on your computer has never been so easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distant Travels</title>
      <link>https://patriktrefil.com/posts/distant_travels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 17:10:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patriktrefil.com/posts/distant_travels/</guid>
      <description>I was watching the sun go down when out of the blue a flying pirate-like ship appeared. I thought I was in a dream, but soon I realised that was not the case. Even though I had chills going down my spine, my curiosity kept me sitting on the cliff. I was quiet and still; I could hear my own heartbeat.
I was convinced the ship would pass by without the crew noticing me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out of style</title>
      <link>https://patriktrefil.com/posts/out_of_style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 09:56:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patriktrefil.com/posts/out_of_style/</guid>
      <description>Out of Style The world we live in today is a complicated, fast-paced place with many problems. I want to dedicate this essay to the environmental and ethical issues while keeping the focus predominantly on (fast) fashion and its impacts. I consider raising awareness about consumerism and the materialistic character of society vital, since it may very well destroy our planet. Fast fashion is, by its definition, a production of inexpensive clothing by mass-market retailers in response to the latest trends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good or bad</title>
      <link>https://patriktrefil.com/posts/good_or_bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 09:50:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patriktrefil.com/posts/good_or_bad/</guid>
      <description>Good or bad? Have you ever asked yourself the question where does the ability to decide what is and is not moral come from? What has shaped our moral beliefs? Is our moral code determined more by our genetics or by our environment we live in ? All of these are difficult questions and I am going to attempt to answer them in this text. This essay is going to explore the impacts of genetics, religion and culture, environment and upbringing on human&amp;rsquo;s moral principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limit(less)</title>
      <link>https://patriktrefil.com/posts/limitless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 09:50:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patriktrefil.com/posts/limitless/</guid>
      <description>Limit(less) Potential is defined as someone&amp;rsquo;s or something&amp;rsquo;s ability to develop, achieve, or succeed according to the Cambridge English Dictionary. In this essay, I would like to focus predominantly on the potential of individuals and its limitations. This is an important topic for every single one of us, considering potential is what makes us motivated and excited about the future. I think the significance is best explained by this quote from Zig Zaglar:&amp;quot; When you catch a glimpse of your potential, that&amp;rsquo;s when passion is born.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
